<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflection on David Haney - Blogging my experiences as a developer and engineering manager.</title>
    <link>https://www.davidhaney.io/tags/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflection on David Haney - Blogging my experiences as a developer and engineering manager.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>David Haney</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 12:07:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.davidhaney.io/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better MIME Mapping Stealer!</title>
      <link>https://www.davidhaney.io/a-better-mime-mapping-stealer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 12:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidhaney.io/a-better-mime-mapping-stealer/</guid>
      <description>In the interest of self-improvement and sharing knowledge, I felt that I should share an update to my last post. I discovered a slightly better way to create the GetMimeMapping delegate/method via reflection that involves less casting and overhead, and is more Object Oriented in a sense. It allows the signature of the reflected method to be Funcinstead of MethodInfo. Code below, note the use of Delegate.CreateDelegate(Type, MethodInfo):
/// &amp;lt;summary&amp;gt; /// Exposes the Mime Mapping method that Microsoft hid from us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determine MIME Type from File Name</title>
      <link>https://www.davidhaney.io/determine-mime-type-from-file-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 15:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidhaney.io/determine-mime-type-from-file-name/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a need, in an ASP.NET MVC3 application, to read raw HTML, CSS, JS, and image files from disk and return them to the user&amp;#8230; A sort of &amp;#8220;pass-through&amp;#8221; if you will. Normally I&amp;#8217;d have simply routed to a custom HTTP handler per file type or just allowed MVC3 to map existing files to supply its own .NET HTTP handlers and do all of this work for me, but in this case I needed the mapped &amp;#8220;directory&amp;#8221; to switch behind the scenes based on Session settings&amp;#8230; So I ultimately had to feed these files through a Controller and Action Method to gain access to the Session.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>