<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on David Haney - Blogging About .NET Core &amp; Engineering Management</title>
    <link>https://www.davidhaney.io/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on David Haney - Blogging About .NET Core &amp; Engineering Management</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>David Haney</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 17:27:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.davidhaney.io/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Great Junior Tech Résumé</title>
      <link>https://www.davidhaney.io/writing-a-great-junior-tech-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.davidhaney.io/writing-a-great-junior-tech-resume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks back I wrote this tweet:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-dnt=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I did a presentation / speaking thing last week that got me thinking: would it be useful to blog about how to build a resume as someone new to tech, from the perspective of a hiring manager? I might whip that up today or tomorrow if people like the idea.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; David Haney hachyderm.io/@haney (@haneytron) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/haneytron/status/1016417664766443520?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;July 9, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;43 likes later, it&amp;rsquo;s clear to me that this topic is in-demand. So, let&amp;rsquo;s skip over the pleasantries and talk about how you can create a great technical résumé as a junior developer, from the perspective of me (a hiring manager).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Blog &amp; Hiring Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.davidhaney.io/new-blog-and-hiring-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 13:56:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.davidhaney.io/new-blog-and-hiring-needs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I failed badly in my mission to blog every week of 2017. I guess life and stuff just got in the way in the end. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to be more consistent in the second half of 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I bring some news: I have a new blog engine, and we are hiring at Stack Overflow!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;new-blog-engine&#34;&gt;New blog engine&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was previously using WordPress but had many issues and concerns with it. One of the biggest concerns was that the site was not mobile friendly, and making it responsive was next to impossible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Hiring: Developers Are Like Stocks</title>
      <link>https://www.davidhaney.io/on-hiring-developers-are-like-stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 11:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.davidhaney.io/on-hiring-developers-are-like-stocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is for those of you who hire developers, and also junior developers who want to be hired. Let’s talk about how developers are just like individual stocks in the stock market. Time for a little role-playing: you’re now a stock market investor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a financial advisor, your company has given you $2,000,000 USD to invest in the stock market. It’s made very clear that the future of the company depends on the return on investment (herein called ROI) – “gains” – that your investments bring to the company. Your decisions will have a major impact on the company’s future. Given that kind of pressure, what’s your investment strategy for success? Begin by reviewing the kinds of stocks available to invest in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developer Turned Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.davidhaney.io/developer-turned-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 14:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.davidhaney.io/developer-turned-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February of 2015, I was promoted to Engineering Manager at Stack Overflow. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/The_Hitchhiker%27s_Guide_to_the_Galaxy#Chapter_1_2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This has made a lot of people very angry and been widely regarded as a bad move&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are tons of things I’ve learned so far, some of which I’ve learned the hard way. There’s also a world of difference between managing code, and managing people who code. Your day to day work routine changes completely. You define success differently. You feel a little bit like you just rebooted your career and are starting over at the bottom of the skills ladder. It’s intimidating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
